Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1903-1981 (Boxes 16-24)
  - Rossiia i Slavianstvo, printed copies
    - "Zametki pisatelia," "Literatura," "Literaturnaia Gazeta," printed copies
      - "Iz vospominanii o S.-Peterburgskom universitete,", 1930 February (Box-folder 19: 20)
      - "Liubovnik Ellady,", 1930 March (Box-folder 19: 21)
      - "Iz vospominanii o Vladimire Solov'eve,", 1930 September (Box-folder 19: 22)
      - "Pushkinizm i Pushkin,", 1931 September (Box-folder 19: 23)
      - "Pamiati V.O. Kliuchevskago,", 1931 December (Box-folder 19: 24)
      - "Pamiati Maksimiliana A. Voloshina. Stranichka iz vospominanii,", 1932 August (Box-folder 19: 25)
      - "K kharakteristike M. Voloshina,", 1932 September (Box-folder 19: 26)
      - "K stoletiiu smerti Val'ter skotta...,", 1932 October (Box-folder 19: 27)
      - "Iubilei Sovremennykh Zapisok,", 1932 November (Box-folder 19: 28)
      - "Ob odnom al'bome pushkinskoi epokhi,", 1932 December (Box-folder 19: 29)
      - "'Putivoditel' po Pushkinu',", 1932 December (Box-folder 19: 30)
      - "O Fete--'porzrevala'-li Rossiia Feta?,", 1933 February (Box-folder 19: 31)
      - "Russko-Slavianskie pominki,", 1933 August (Box-folder 19: 32)
      - "I.S. Turgenev, kak politicheskii myslitel',", 1933 October (Box-folder 19: 33)
      - "Nikita Muraviev i Pavel Pestel,", 1934 March (Box-folder 19: 34)
      - "D.I. Mendeleev,", 1934 April (Box-folder 19: 35)
      - "Liga Russkoi Kul'tury,", 1934 June (Box-folder 19: 36)
  - Mech, "Dnevnik politika," printed copies
    - "Na putiakh k tserkovnomu ob"edineniiu,", 1935 November (Box-folder 19: 37)
    - "Zametki pisatelia. Dvazhdy dva piat'--premilaia veshchitsa,", 1935 November (Box-folder 19: 38)
      Includes introduction by Gleb Struve, "P.B. Struve ob antisemitizme," typescript, undated.
    - "Dnevnik politika. Iupiter i Iunona v odnom litse,", 1935 December (Box-folder 19: 39)
    - "M.V. Chelnokov i D.N. Shipov. Stranichka iz moikh vospominanii,", 1935 December (Box-folder 19: 40)
  - General
    - Bibliography of articles published by P. B. Struve, handwritten catalogue, undated (Box-folder 19: 41-42)
    - Finland. Newspaper articles (Box-folder 19: 43)
    - Library request cards and miscellaneous holograph notes, 1940s (Box-folder 19: 44)
    - List of articles published without author's signature in Vozrozhdenie, Rossiia and Rossiia i Slavianstvo, typescript, undated (Box-folder 19: 45)
    - Miscellaneous short writings
      - Excerpts, typescript, photocopies and holograph, 1919 (Box-folder 19: 46)
      - Printed copies, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 19: 47)
    - Notebooks, holograph, undated (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
    - Notecards, research material for chapters re Novgorod and Pskov, holograph, undated (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - Obituaries, printed copies from various publications, 1919-1936 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Posthumously published articles, 1948-1981 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - "The Bolshevik Campaign Amongst the Coloured People of the East," typescript of speech, undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - "Bossiue i T'er," Rossiia (?), printed copy, undated (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - "Emigratsiia dolzhna osoznat' ne svoiu otorvannost' ot Rossii, no svoiu s nei sviazannost'," holograph, undated (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - "Georg fon Belov," holograph, undated (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Interview, holograph and typescript copies, undated (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - "Istorcheskii smysl Bol'shevizma," holograph, undated (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - "Istoriko-sotsiologicheskie nabliudeniia nad razvitiem russkogo pis'mennogo iazyka," typescript, undated (Box-folder 20: 12)
    - "Kniaz' Gr. Nik. Trubetskoi v Serbii, vospominaniia ego sotrudnika," typescript with holograph annotations, undated (Box-folder 20: 13)
    - "Kratkii obzor istorii russkogo prava," holograph and typescript copies, undated (Box-folder 20: 14)
    - "Masonstvo," holograph and typescript copies, undated (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - "Memorandum," holograph and typescript copies, undated (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - "Moi vstrechi i stolknoveniia s Leninym," typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - "My Contacts With Rodichev," printed copy, undated (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - "Nashi chuvstva i nash dolg," holograph, undated (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - "Nelepye intrigi i intrizhnye nelepitsy," holograph, undated (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - "Neskol'ko myslei o bol'shevikakh i Leninizme," holograph, undated (Box-folder 21: 7)
    - "Osnovnoi zakon gosudarstva o grazhdanskoi rente," typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - "Politicheskiia techeniia i nastroeniia v ..." (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - "Predislovie k al'bomu," Rossiia i Slavianstvo, holograph, undated (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - "Predislovie k Sborniku Pamiati Kniazia G. Trebetskogo,", undated (Box-folder 21: 11)
    - "Rech' v pamiat' P.I. Novgorodtseva," holograph and typescript copy, undated (Box-folder 21: 12)
    - "Richard Wagner und Karl Marx," holograph, undated (Box-folder 21: 13)
    - "Sotsializm," holograph manuscript, undated (Box-folder 21: 14-18)
    - Speech addressing "La Vague Rouge," holograph and typescript copies, undated (Box-folder 21: 19)
    - "Zametki pisatelia. Pushkin i Frantsuzskie romantiki," Rossiia (?), printed copy, undated (Box-folder 21: 20)
    - Speech at "Predparlament," photocopies of clippings, 1917 (Box-folder 21: 21)
    - "Problema kapitala v sisteme politicheskoi ekonomii, postroennoi na poniatii tseny," Izvestiia Rossiiskoi Akademii Nauk, printed copy, 1917 (Box-folder 21: 22)
    - Vremena, written under pseudonym Sergei Lunin, 1919?
      - Holograph excerpts, 1919 (Box-folder 21: 23)
      - Clippings of excerpts published in Vozrozhdenie, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 21: 24)
      - Typescript excerpts, undated (Box-folder 21: 25)
    - Excelsior, questionnaire and responses, 1920 October 11 (Box-folder 21: 26)
    - Obshchee Delo, questionnaire and responses, holograph and typescript copies, 1920 (Box-folder 21: 27)
    - Russian refugees, holograph and typescript notes, 1920? (Box-folder 21: 28)
    - "Gotovo li bezhenstvo skazat' svoe slovo o russkikh delakh?," typescript draft, 1923? (Box-folder 21: 29)
    - "Beloe dvizhenie i Dobrovol'cheskaia Armiia," typescript draft with holograph corrections, 1924 (Box-folder 21: 30)
    - "Dnevnik Politika," holograph drafts, 1926 (Box-folder 21: 31)
    - Interview with J. Benoist-Mechin, Paris, typescript copy with annotations, 1926 March (Box-folder 21: 32)
    - "Arrivist bol'shevizma,", 1928 September? (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - "Rusky komunismus a svetova civilisace," Nar. Listy, printed copy, 1930 October (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - "K. A. Nevolin (1806-1855) i A. A. Kunik (1814-1899)," speech at the Russian Scientific Institute, Belgrade, typescript copy, 1931 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - "F.I. Rodichev i moi vstrechi s nim," typescript, 1933 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - "Protiv maloveriia i malodushiia," Russkii Invalid, 1934 May (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - "Na putiakh k tserkovnomu ob"edineniiu," Russkii Invalid, 1935 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - "Predmetno-teoreticheski osnovi na stopanskata nauka i tekhnite metodologicheski posledstviia," in Bulgarian and German, publications of the Statistical Institute for Economic Research, State University of Sofia, Bulgaria, No. 4, printed copy, 1936 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Dukh i slovo Pushkina, printed copy, 1937 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Koniunkturata kato stopansko-teoreticheski problem, printed copy, 1937 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - "Anglichane, kak osnovateli krupnoi tkachepechatnoi promyshlennosti v Rossii i sud'by russkoi tekstil'noi promyshlennosti,", 1938?
      - Holograph, undated (Box-folder 22: 10)
      - "Zapiski russkoi akademicheskoi gruppy v S.Sh.A.,", 1969 (Box-folder 22: 11)
        Reprint of article written in 1938 and first published in English in 1939-1940.
    - "Rastushchii i zhivoi Pushkin," printed copy, 1937 January (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - "S.P. Shneerev i zapadnyia vnusheniia i istochniki teorii-aforizma o 'gnilom' ili gniiushchem' zapade," tearsheets of article, 1939 (Box-folder 22: 13)
    - Dva aspekta vtoroi mirovoi voiny, draft of table of contents, typescript, 1940 (Box-folder 22: 14)
      Includes excerpts from correspondence.
    - "V. G. Vasil'evskii kak iszledovatel' sotsial'noi istorii drevnosti kak uchitel' nauki," printed copy, 1940 (Box-folder 22: 15)
    - Sotsial'naia i ekonomicheskaia istoriia Rossii s dreveneishego vremeni do nashego, v sviazi s razvitiem russkoi kul'tury i rostom rossiiskoi gosudarstvennosti, 1952
      - "Sotsial'naia i ekonomicheskaia istoriia Rossii s drevnikh vreman do nashego vremeni," typescript draft with holograph annotations, 1938 (Box-folder 22: 16-19)
      - "Sotsial'naia i ekonomicheskaia istoriia Rossii s drevnikh vreman do nashego vremeni," typescript draft with holograph annotations, 1938 (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - Correspondence
        - Struve, Arkadii with Gleb Struve, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 23: 2)
        - Struve, Gleb and Aleksei with Baron Boris Nol'de, 1944-1948 (Box-folder 23: 3)
      - Draft of preface, typescript, undated (Box-folder 23: 4)
      - Drafts of bibliographies of Petr Struve's work composed by Gleb, Aleksei and Nikita Struve, typescript and holograph, 1949 (Box-folder 23: 5)
      - Miscellaneous material re publication of Petr Struve's works, 1949 (Box-folder 23: 6)
        Includes typescript and holograph notes by Gleb and Aleksei Struve.
      - Publication committee, drafts of letters, 1950 (Box-folder 23: 7)
      - Order lists, 1952 (Box-folder 23: 8)
      - Review, Russkaia Zhizn', 1953 January 13 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - "Le Socialisme," Le Contrat Social, Volume V, No. 2, printed copy, 1961 March/April (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - Dukh i Slovo, Y.M.C.A. Press, Paris, 1981
      - Correspondence between Gleb and Nikita Struve re publication, 1972 (Box-folder 23: 11)
        Includes typescript lists of Petr Struve's articles published in periodical press.
      - Articles chosen for publication by Gleb Struve but not included in the published volume, 1926-1934
        Typescript copies of work originally published in Vozrozhdenie, Rossiia and Rossiia i slavianstvo.
        - "Dmitrii L'vovich Kriukov,", undated (Box-folder 23: 12)
        - "O memuaromanii nashego vremeni,", undated (Box-folder 23: 13)
        - "Pis'mo tuda,", undated (Box-folder 23: 14)
        - "Rech' pamiati P.I. Novgorodtseva,", undated (Box-folder 23: 15)
        - "V.K. Dmitriev,", 1913 (Box-folder 23: 16)
        - "Novaia kniga po istorii religioznoi filosofii," review of Fritz Lieb, Franz Baaders Jugendgeschichte. Die Fruehentwicklung eines Romantickers, 1926 (Box-folder 23: 17)
        - "Optina Pustyn' i ee starchestvo," review of Rev. Sergei Chetverikov's book Optina Pustyn', 1926 (Box-folder 23: 18)
        - "Po povodu knigi N.S. Arsevieva o pravoslavnom blagochestii," review of N. Arseniev's Die Kirche des Morgenlandes. Weltanschauung und Frommigkeitsleben, 1926 (Box-folder 23: 19)
        - "Vostochnoe khristianstvo, ili pravoslavie v otsenke zapadnykh bogoslovov," review of N. Arseniev, Mysticism and the Eastern Church, 1926 (Box-folder 23: 20)
        - "25-letie Politekhnicheskogo Instituta imeni Imperatora Petra Velikogo,", 1927 (Box-folder 23: 21)
        - "Eshche o znakomykh Pushkina i Bal'zaka,", 1927 (Box-folder 23: 22)
        - "Otkuda slovo 'bezhenets'? Skol'ko let ..." (Box-folder 23: 23)
        - "Pamiati A.F.Koni,", 1927 (Box-folder 23: 24)
        - "S.F. Platonov o Petre Velikom,", 1927 (Box-folder 23: 25)
        - "S.V. Lurie. Nekrolog,", 1927 (Box-folder 23: 26)
        - "Istoricheskoe prozrenie Ivana Aksakova o Serbii i serbakh," clipping, 1928 (Box-folder 23: 27)
        - "Ob epigrammaticheskom rode',", 1928 (Box-folder 23: 28)
        - "Velikii Kniaz' Nikolai Mikhailovich,", 1927 (Box-folder 23: 29)
        - "K Tat'ianinu Dniu. Razmyshleniia,", 1928 (Box-folder 23: 30)
        - "Razocharovannye Otechestvennye Zapiski,", 1928 (Box-folder 23: 31)
        - "Revoliutsiia i iazyk,", 1928 (Box-folder 23: 32)
        - "Iz universitetskikh vospominanii,", 1929 (Box-folder 23: 33)
        - "Pamiati A.A. Manuilova," clipping, 1929 (Box-folder 23: 34)
        - "Pamiati E.L. Radlova,", 1929 (Box-folder 23: 35)
        - "Eduard Meier,", 1930 (Box-folder 23: 36)
        - "K.P. Kramarzh. Opyt kharakteristiki i slovo priznatel'nosti,", 1930 (Box-folder 23: 37)
        - "Istoriia vseobshchaia i istoriia tserkovnaia v ikh vzaimootnosheniiakh," review of E. C. Scherer, Geschichte und Kirchengeschichte an den deutschen Universitaeten, 1930 (Box-folder 23: 38)
        - "Iz vospominanii o S.-Peterburgskom Universitete,", 1930 (Box-folder 23: 39)
        - "Pamiati dorogogo druga. Kniaz' Grigorii Nikolaevich Trubetskoi,", 1930 (Box-folder 23: 40)
        - "1500-letie smerti blazhennogo Avgustina,", 1930 (Box-folder 23: 41)
        - "80-letie T.G. Masarika,", 1930 (Box-folder 23: 42)
        - "Aleksandr II,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 43)
        - "GPU nauchnoi mysli,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 44)
        - "Lichnaia svoboda i natsional'naia gosudarstvennost',", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 45)
        - "Moskovskii Universitet. K Tat'ianinu dniu,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 46)
        - "Piatidesiatiletie zamechatel'noi russkoi knigi,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 47)
        - "Pritiagatel'naia sila i vnutrenniia moshch' russkoi kul'tury,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 48)
        - "Uchenyi, deiatel', mudrets. Rech' pamiati N.I. Pirogova,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 49)
        - "Velikii russkii filolog A.KH. Vostokov -- perevodchik serbskikh narodnykh pesen,", 1931 (Box-folder 23: 50)
        - "Graf N. P. Ignatiev. K stoletiiu so dnia ego rozhdeniia,", 1932 (Box-folder 23: 51)
        - 'Kul'tura i politika, kul'tura i natsional'nost'. Zavety Pushkina,", 1932 (Box-folder 23: 52)
        - "Moskva i S.-Peterburg,", 1932 (Box-folder 23: 53)
        - "Pamiati A.A. Branta,", 1932 (Box-folder 23: 54)
        - "Tri russkikh zhenshchiny. Pamiati I. F. Dubasovoi, E. K. Chenokovoi i E. A. Rodichevoi,", 1932 (Box-folder 23: 55)
        - "Bismark ili Gitler? Tridtsat' tezisov o natsionalizme i o konservativnoi demokratii,", 1933 (Box-folder 23: 56)
        - "Gosudarstvennoe darovanie i politicheskii lik P.N. Vrangelia,", 1933 (Box-folder 24: 1)
        - "Krupnyi uchenyi i khoroshii chelovek. Pamiati S.S. Kona,", 1933 (Box-folder 24: 2)
        - "Liberalizm, demokratiia, konservatizm i sovremennye dvizheniia i techeniia,", 1933 (Box-folder 24: 3)
        - "Nezabyvaemyi starets. Pamiati grafa K.A. Khreptovicha-Buteneva," clipping, 1933 (Box-folder 24: 4)
        - "Russko-Slavianskie pominki. V.I. Lamanskii. A.N. Pypin. N.A. Popov,", 1933 (Box-folder 24: 5)
        - "D.I. Mendeleev,", 1934 (Box-folder 24: 6)
        - "Kul'tura i politika,", 1934 (Box-folder 24: 7)
        - "Pamiati V.E. Dena,", 1934 (Box-folder 24: 8)
        - "Posledniia kniga Osval'da Spenglera, buria protiv nego i rokovoi postanovlennyi im vopros,", 1934 (Box-folder 24: 9)
        - Miscellaneous drafts and notes (Box-folder 24: 10-11)
- FILES CREATED AS EDITOR AND CONTRIBUTOR, 1914-1934 (Boxes 24-37)
  Material related to Petr Struve's work with Vozrozhdenie, Rossiia and Rossiia i Slavianstvo. Includes holograph and typescript copies of articles submitted for publication and business and personal correspondence of editorial office.
  - Rossiia, 1925-1931
    - Correspondence, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 24: 12-13)
    - Articles submitted for publication, unless otherwise indicated, 1927-1928
      - Anonymous and unsigned
        - "Nam pishut iz Veny," holograph (Box-folder 24: 14)
        - "Poetessa, kot i tishina," holograph (Box-folder 24: 15)
        - "Tserkovnoe upravlenie za rubezhom," holograph (Box-folder 24: 16)
        - "Tsyrk 'br. Stanevskikh'," holograph (Box-folder 24: 17)
        - "Tukhachevskii i Evraziitsy," typescript (Box-folder 24: 18)
        - Untitled excerpts from correspondence re church situation in Soviet Union, holograph (Box-folder 24: 19)
        - Poems, holograph (Box-folder 24: 20)
      - A.P., "Rossiia i cheshskaia nezavisimost'" (Box-folder 24: 21)
      - Amfiteatrov, A., "General Petr Zhivkovich - vospominanii zhurnalista," holograph (Box-folder 24: 22)
      - Anichkova, S. (Taube), 2 poems, typescript (Box-folder 24: 23)
      - Aristov, A., review of "Sozvuchiia Novogo Zaveta," typescript (Box-folder 24: 24)
      - Arkhangel'skii, G., "Zakon No. 1 ili osnovnoi zakon ob organizatsii vlasti v Rossiiskom Gosudarstve," holograph (Box-folder 24: 25)
      - Borin, N.
        - "Tsar'-Osvoboditel' v Bolgarii," holograph (Box-folder 24: 26)
        - "Vrednaia 'perepiska'," holograph (Box-folder 24: 27)
      - Burnakin, A., "'Osvag' zagranitsei," typescript (Box-folder 24: 28)
      - Byval'kevich, P., "A. F. Koni," holograph (Box-folder 24: 29)
      - Davats, V.
        - "Dva slova o 'Filippiatakh'," typescript (Box-folder 24: 30)
        - "Vrangel' v Gallipoli," holograph (Box-folder 24: 31)
      - Dmitrieva, E., "G. P. Stamatov," holograph (Box-folder 25: 1)
      - Finisov, P., "Klevetnikam Rossii" (Box-folder 25: 2)
      - Forshteter, M., "Strategicheskaia planirovka Parizha," holograph (Box-folder 25: 3)
      - Fulop-Miller, Rene, "The Mind and Face of Bolshevism: An Examination of Cultural Life in Soviet Russia," typescript (Box-folder 25: 4)
      - Glebov, Sergei, "K poliakam," a poem, holograph (Box-folder 25: 5)
      - Gulkevich, A., "Molitva Pushkina," holograph (Box-folder 25: 6)
      - Ivanov, Victor, "Skala," holograph (Box-folder 25: 7)
      - Karpov, M., "Vragi," holograph (Box-folder 25: 8)
      - Kharlamov, V., "Russkie monarkhisty v emigratsii," typescript translation of article from Kozacky Smer, printed copy, 1925 (Box-folder 25: 9)
      - Krasil'nikov, A., "Arkhiologicheskiia zametki," "Khram-pamiatnik," "Mysli vslukh," "Staryia novosti," holograph (Box-folder 25: 10)
      - Ladnov, Evgenii, "Trotskii - Messiia," "V. V. Shul'gin i V. V. Shul'gin," "Konstrabandistry," "Trest," "Tri stolitsky," holograph (Box-folder 25: 11)
      - Levin, S., "Fashistskoe gosudarstvo," holograph (Box-folder 25: 12)
      - Liubin, V., "Stikhi," holograph (Box-folder 25: 13)
      - M. V., "Poema o Bedlame," typescript, 1931 (Box-folder 25: 14)
      - Mel'gunov, S., rejected article, holograph (Box-folder 25: 15)
      - N., "Na vechere Valentina Gorianskago," holograph (Box-folder 25: 16)
      - Nemirin, N., "Pis'ma iz Iugoslavii," holograph (Box-folder 25: 17)
      - Nikolaev, S., "Otnositel'nost'," holograph, undated (Box-folder 25: 18)
      - Otman, Sergei
        - "O Pravoslavnom torzhestve v Podkarpatskoi Rusi," holograph (Box-folder 25: 19)
        - "A. F. Koni - iz lichnykh vospominanii" (Box-folder 25: 20)
        - "Iz proshlago" (Box-folder 25: 21)
      - Privalov, M., "Russkii gosudarstvennyi khor," typescript (Box-folder 25: 22)
      - Sablin, E. V., five letters from London (Box-folder 25: 23)
      - Sergeev, Kh. (Box-folder 25: 24)
      - Shefer, Igor, "Rossiia," poem, typescript (Box-folder 25: 25)
      - Sheika, T. V., "K protsesu Shvartsbarda," holograph (Box-folder 25: 26)
      - Semernikov, A., "Deviatyi krug," holograph (Box-folder 25: 27)
      - Shmurlo, E.(?), untitled typescript, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 25: 28)
      - Shumanskii, K., "K stoletiiu Navarinskoi bitvy," holograph (Box-folder 25: 29)
      - Silevin, "Beseda s litovskim poslannikom vo Frantsii," typescript draft (Box-folder 25: 30)
      - Skrypnitskii, M., "Byt' ili ne byt' sotsialistom," holograph (Box-folder 25: 31)
      - Soiuz Russkikh Zhurnalistov i Literatorov v Germanii, untitled article re censorship in the Soviet Union, typescript (Box-folder 25: 32)
      - Spadrin, Aleksei, "Ob avtoritetakh i vozhdiakh," holograph (Box-folder 25: 33)
      - Struve, Konstantin, "Vynuzhdennoe razdelenie prikhoda," holograph (Box-folder 25: 34)
      - Struve, Lev, "Nado, umet' teriat'," holograph (Box-folder 25: 35)
      - Sukapton, Baron Girard de (?), reports on trial of Anatolii Erokhin, typescript and holograph (Box-folder 25: 36)
      - Tideman, I., "Evrazii," typescript (Box-folder 25: 37)
      - Tkachenko, Ippolit, "Etapy v zhizni moego druga Pavla Iks - ne skazka, a byl'," holograph (Box-folder 25: 38)
      - Tkhorzhevskii, "Pesnia," holograph (Box-folder 25: 39)
      - Tsurikov, N.
        - Fragment of memoir, galley proof (Box-folder 25: 40)
        - "Pamiati pavshykh," galley proof (Box-folder 25: 41)
        - "Za Rossiiu - Mariia Vladislavovna Zakhartchenko- Shul'ts," typescript (Box-folder 25: 42)
        - "Milenko i Piliukov - malen'kii fel'eton," Rossiia i Slavianstvo (Paris), holograph (Box-folder 25: 43)
      - Veteran, "Iz proshlago," holograph (Box-folder 25: 44)
      - Zabello, N., "Situatsiia na Ukraine," holograph (Box-folder 25: 45)
      - Zarubezhnyi, A., "Prokliatyi god," holograph (Box-folder 25: 46)
      - Zhyzhnevskii, A., "Polkovnik A.O. Tsybul'skii. Nekrolog," typescript (Box-folder 25: 47)
    - Reports from "Russunion" and "Russpress," typescript (Box-folder 25: 48)
  - Russkaia Mysl', 1914-1926
    Articles submitted for publication.
    - Anonymous, "Zhiva nasha Rossiia, zhiva," typescript, 1924 (Box-folder 25: 49)
    - Abrosimov, M., "Fakty i tendensii raspredeleniia obshchestvennogo bogatstva i dokhoda," typescript and holograph (Box-folder 25: 50)
    - Baikov, Boris, "Angliia i Rossiia v Persii i bol'shevistskaia avantiura," typescript (Box-folder 25: 51)
    - Bernadskii, G. V., review of Evraziiskii Vremennik, typescript (Box-folder 25: 52)
    - Bilimovich, A. D., review of Dagoljub Yovanovitch's "Le rendement optimum du travail ouvrier" and "Les stimulants modernes du travail ouvrier-essai de bibliographie systematique" (1923), holograph (Box-folder 25: 53)
    - Brianchaninov, N. V., "Iz nedavnego proshligo," holograph (Box-folder 25: 54)
    - Brutskus, B. D.
      - "Russkaia agrarnaia revoliutsiia i ee uroki," holograph (Box-folder 25: 55)
      - Review on I. Cherikover's "Antisemitism i pogromy na Ukraine, 1917-1918," holograph (Box-folder 25: 56)
    - Chetverikov, S. I., "Sibir' i moia v nei deiatel' nost'," typescript, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 25: 57)
    - Chokin, G., untitled holograph text, 1926 (Box-folder 25: 58)
    - Demosfenov, S. S., "Ocherki prodovol'stvennogo dela v nedalekom proshlom," typescript (Box-folder 25: 59)
    - Despotuli, Vladimir, review of A. Emil'ianov's "Persidksii front," typescript, 1924 (Box-folder 25: 60)
    - Engel', Robert, "Muzyka i kul'tura," typescript (Box-folder 25: 61)
    - Eropkin, A., "Russkie finansy. Referat Obshchestvu Russkikh Uchenykh v Belgrade," holograph (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - Goldenveizer, Ia. S., letter from Kiev, 1922 (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Golovin, N. N., "Uroki voenno-istoricheskoi nauki, novye dokumenty o konnom boe u derevni Volchkovtsy 8-go avgusta goda," typescript, 1914 (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Grabbe, Elizabeta, "To chto vspomnilos'," typescript, 1923 (Box-folder 26: 4)
    - Grimm, E. D., "Bez dogmata," typescript (Box-folder 26: 5)
    - Ianishevskii, A., "O strakhe i znachenii ego, kak faktora sovremennoi deistvietl'nosti. Opyt biologo- psikhologicheskogo issledovaniia sovremennykh sobytii," typescript, 1921 (Box-folder 26: 6)
    - Kirilov, A., "Filosofskoe mirosozertsanie General- Leitenanta M. K. Diterikhs," holograph, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - Kolpakchi, G., on the subject of Professor S. Metal'nikov's article "Materializm i mirovaia ..." (Box-folder 26: 8)
    - Kritskii, Mikhail, "Krasnaia armiia na Iuzhnom fronte v gg.," typescript, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 26: 9)
    - Lamanskii, V. V., "Omskie mysli," typescript, 1923 (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - Lopatina, E. M., "Narod-bogonosets," holograph (Box-folder 26: 11)